<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- linking xml to the the xsl file -->
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="stations.xsl"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="history.xsl"?>

<!-- linking xml to the the DTD file -->
<!DOCTYPE stations SYSTEM "stations.dtd">

<!-- Build up the node tree to contain all the elements -->
<stations>
    <!-- Here is the station element contain an attribute to define whether the station is open or under building -->
    <station type="opened">
        <!-- Here is the image element contain image name -->
        <img>
            <imgName>Euston.jpg</imgName>
        </img>
        
        <!-- Here is the name element contain current and used name -->
        <name>
            <currentName>Euston</currentName>
        </name>
        
        <!-- Here is the information element contain all the rest details -->
        <information>
            <position>
                <postcode> NW1 2DU </postcode>
                <lineAdress>
                    Euston Station
                    Kings Cross, London
                </lineAdress>
            </position>
            <openedTime>
                <date> 22 </date>
                <month> June </month>
                <year> 1907 </year>
            </openedTime>
            <zones>1</zones>
            <lines>Northern</lines>
            <lines>Victoria</lines>
            <usage>43.10</usage>
            <history>
                Most of the C&amp;SLR's route had been constructed with tunnels 10 feet 2 inches (3.10 m) or 10 feet 6 inches (3.20 m) in diameter, smaller than the 11 feet 6 inches (3.51 m) diameter that had been adopted as the standard for the CCE&amp;HR and other deep level tube lines. The smaller tunnel size restricted the capacity of the C&amp;SLR's trains and, in 1912, the C&amp;SLR published a bill for their enlargement. A separate bill was published at the same time by the London Electric Railway (LER), that included plans to construct tunnels to connect the C&amp;SLR at Euston to the CCE&amp;HR's station at Camden Town. Together, the works proposed in these bills would enable trains of each company to run over the route of the other, effectively combining the two separate railways. The reconstruction and extension works were postponed during World War I and did not begin until 1922. The C&amp;SLR platforms and the tunnels between Euston and Moorgate were closed for the reconstruction on 8 August 1922. They reopened on 20 April 1924 along with the new link to Camden Town.
            </history>
        </information>
    </station>
    
    
    <station type="opened">
        <img>
            <imgName>Amersham.jpg</imgName>
        </img>
        <name>
            <usedName>Amersham &amp; Chesham Bois</usedName>
            <currentName>Amersham</currentName>
        </name>
        <information>
            <position>
                <postcode>HP6 5AZ</postcode>
                <lineAdress>Amersham</lineAdress>
            </position>
            <openedTime>
                <date> 9 </date>
                <month> September </month>
                <year> 1892 </year>
            </openedTime>
            <zones>9</zones>
            <lines>Metropolitan</lines>
            <usage>2.36</usage>
            <history>
                The station was opened on 1 September 1892 as part of the Metropolitan Railway (Met) extension from Chalfont Road (now Chalfont &amp; Latimer) to Aylesbury. On 12 March 1922, its name was changed to "Amersham &amp; Chesham Bois", but the original name was restored during 1937.
                
                From 16 March 1899, the Great Central Railway served the station through its extension to Marylebone. Consequently, the station became joint Met/GCR owned. On 1 January 1923, the GCR became part of the London and North Eastern Railway (LNER) as part of the Railways Act 1921, and on 1 July 1933, the Met became part of the London Passenger Transport Board (LPTB), thus becoming the Metropolitan line of the London Underground. On 1 January 1948, the LNER was nationalised, its share of the station initially coming under the control of the Eastern Region of British Railways, before being transferred to the London Midland Region in 1958.
                
                On 12 September 1960, the tracks from Rickmansworth to Amersham were electrified, partially fulfilling plans first proposed some thirty years earlier. The rolling stock ordered by London Underground as part of this project, the A60 stock, is named after Amersham.
            </history>
        </information>
    </station>
    
    
    
    <station type="opened">
        <img>
            <imgName>bakerStreet.jpg</imgName>
        </img>
        <name>
            <currentName> Baker Street </currentName>
        </name>
        <information>
            <position>
                <postcode> HA3 8NT </postcode>
                <lineAdress> Forward Drive, Christchurch Avenue, Harrow </lineAdress>
            </position>
            <openedTime> 
                <date> 10 </date>
                <month> January </month>
                <year> 1863 </year>
            </openedTime>
            <zones> 1 </zones>
            <lines> Metropolitan </lines>
            <lines> Bakerloo </lines>
            <lines> Circle </lines>
            <lines> Jubilee </lines>
            <lines>Hammersmith &amp; City </lines>
            <usage> 29.75 </usage>
            <history> 
                In the first half of the 19th century, the population and physical extent of London grew greatly. The congested streets and the distance to the City from the stations to the north and west prompted many attempts to get parliamentary approval to build new railway lines into the City. In 1852, Charles Pearson planned a railway from Farringdon to King's Cross. Although the plan was supported by the City, the railway companies were not interested and the company struggled to proceed. The Bayswater, Paddington, and Holborn Bridge Railway Company was established to connect the Great Western Railway's (GWR) Paddington station to Pearson's route at King's Cross. A bill was published in November 1852 and in January 1853 the directors held their first meeting and appointed John Fowler as its engineer. Several bills were submitted for a route between Paddington and Farringdon.The company's name was also to be changed again, to Metropolitan Railway and the route was approved on 7 August 1854.
                
            </history>
        </information>
    </station>
    
    
    
    
    <station type="building">
        <img>
            <imgName>Cassiobridge.jpg</imgName>
        </img>
        <name>
            <currentName>Cassiobridge</currentName>
        </name>
        <information>
            <position>
                <postcode>WD18 7QQ</postcode>
                <lineAdress>Cassiobridge Road</lineAdress>
            </position>
            <openedTime>
                <year>2020</year>
            </openedTime>
            <zones>7</zones>
            <lines>Metropolitan</lines>
            <usage>0</usage>
            <history>
                Cassiobridge is a proposed London Underground station in Watford, Hertfordshire, England. The station would be part of the Croxley Rail Link project, a scheme to extend the Metropolitan line to Watford Junction railway station. It would be served by Metropolitan line trains between Watford Junction and Central London via Baker Street. The railway line would run over Ascot Road via a viaduct and the platforms will be situated on the east side of the road. Entrance to the station would be from the west side of the road, with a ticket hall and other facilities at street level. Passengers would gain access to the platforms via stairs and lifts and a short footbridge over the road.
                
                The station is projected to offer interchange with local transport services, and operate as an unstaffed station, providing automatic ticketing facilities similar to a DLR station. There is potential for Park and Ride facilities to be provided, although planning documents indicate high levels of congestion on adjacent roads.
                
            </history>
        </information>
    </station>
    
    
    
    
    <station type="building">
        <img>
            <imgName>NineElms.jpg</imgName>
        </img>
        <name>
            <currentName>Nine Elms</currentName>
        </name>
        <information>
            <position>
                <postcode> SW8 4SR</postcode>
                <lineAdress> 52-, 58 Wandsworth Rd, London </lineAdress>
            </position>
            <openedTime> 
                <year>2020</year> 
            </openedTime>
            <zones> 1 </zones>
            <lines> Northern </lines>
            <usage> 0 </usage>
            <history>
                Nine Elms is a London Underground station under construction in Nine Elms, London, as part of the Northern line extension to Battersea. The station is projected to open along with the rest of the extension in 2020, and will serve the rapidly growing Nine Elms area, New Covent Garden Market and the new Embassy of the United States.
                
                The new station is close to the site of the former Nine Elms railway station, once the terminus of the London and South Western Railway.
            </history>
        </information>
    </station>
    
    
    
    
    <station type="opened">
        <img>
            <imgName>Queensway.jpg</imgName>
        </img>
        <name>
            <usedName>Queen's Road</usedName>
            <currentName>Queensway</currentName>
        </name>
        <information>
            <position>
                <postcode>W2 4RH</postcode>
                <lineAdress>Bayswater Rd, London </lineAdress>
            </position>
            <openedTime>
                <date> 16 </date>
                <month> July </month>
                <year> 1900 </year>
            </openedTime>
            <zones>1</zones>
            <lines>Central</lines>
            <usage>8.71</usage>
            <history>
                It opened on 30 July 1900, as Queen's Road, and was renamed on 1 September 1946. The building is an unusual survivor of the buildings designed for the Central London Railway by Harry Bell Measures, with a flat roof so that commercial development could take place above – in this case, a hotel.
            </history>
        </information>
    </station>
    
    
    
    
    <station type="opened">
        <img>
            <imgName>Waterloo.jpg</imgName>
        </img>
        <name>
            <currentName>Waterloo</currentName>
        </name>
        <information>
            <position>
                <postcode>
                    SE1 8SR
                </postcode>
                <lineAdress>South Bank, London</lineAdress>
            </position>
            <openedTime>
                <date> 1 </date>
                <month> March </month>
                <year> 1906 </year>
            </openedTime>
            <zones>1</zones>
            <lines>Waterloo &amp; City</lines>
            <lines>Bakerloo</lines>
            <lines>Northern</lines>
            <lines>Jubilee</lines>
            <usage>100.36</usage>
            <history>
                The first Underground Line at Waterloo was opened on 8 August 1898 by the Waterloo &amp; City Railway (W&amp;CR), a subsidiary of the owners of the main line station, the London and South Western Railway (L&amp;SWR). The W&amp;CR, nicknamed "The Drain", achieved in a limited way the L&amp;SWR's original plan of taking its tracks the short distance north-east into the City of London.
                
                On 10 March 1906, the Baker Street &amp; Waterloo Railway (BS&amp;WR, now the Bakerloo line) was opened. On 13 September 1926, the extension of the Hampstead &amp; Highgate line (as the Charing Cross branch of the Northern line was then known) was opened from Embankment to the existing City &amp; South London Railway station Kennington with a new station at Waterloo.
                
                As a subsidiary of the L&amp;SWR and its successor, the Southern Railway, the W&amp;CR was not a part of the London Underground system. Following nationalisation of the main line railway companies in 1948, it became part of British Railways (later British Rail).
                
            </history>
        </information>
    </station>
    
    
    
    
    
    <station type="opened">
        <img>
            <imgName>WoodGreen.jpg</imgName>
        </img>
        <name>
            <currentName> Wood Green </currentName>
        </name>
        <information>
            <position>
                <postcode> N22 6EB </postcode>
                <lineAdress> Wood Green, London </lineAdress>
            </position>
            <openedTime>
                <date> 19 </date>
                <month> September </month>
                <year> 1932 </year>
            </openedTime>
            <zones> 3 </zones>
            <lines> Piccadilly </lines>
            <usage> 13.20 </usage>
            <history>
                The station opened on 19 September 1932 when the first section of the Cockfosters extension from Finsbury Park was opened.
                
                Like all stations on the extension, Wood Green set new aesthetic standards, not previously seen on London's Underground. When the Cockfosters extension was planned, alternative names for this station—"Lordship Lane" and "Wood Green Central"—were considered, but rejected. Architecturally, this station, designed by Charles Holden, is a well-preserved example of the modernist house style Holden developed for London Transport in the 1930s. Located on a corner site, the main frontage is curved and is flanked by two ventilation towers, although these are later additions to the station. On the northern side, the structure also incorporates a shop which forms part of the parade in High Road. The other end of the parade features a large London Underground sub-station.
                
                Since July 2011, the station has been a grade II listed building, which now means every station building between Turnpike Lane and Cockfosters is listed.
                
            </history>
        </information>
    </station>
    
    
    
    
    
    <station type="opened">
        <img>
            <imgName>WoodLane.jpg</imgName>
        </img>
        <name>
            <currentName> Wood Lane </currentName>
        </name>
        <information>
            <position>
                <postcode> W12 7SL </postcode>
                <lineAdress> Ariel Way, Shepherd's Bush, London</lineAdress>
            </position>
            <openedTime> 
                <date> 12 </date>
                <month> October </month>
                <year> 2008 </year>
            </openedTime>
            <zones> 2 </zones>
            <lines> Hammersmith &amp; City </lines>
            <lines> Circle </lines>
            <usage> 3.68 </usage>
            <history>
                The Hammersmith and City line was opened on 13 June 1864 by the Metropolitan Railway (MR) as the Hammersmith branch line. The railway became part of London Underground in 1933 and the took on a separate identity as the Hammersmith and City line in 1988.
                
                In 1908 the Franco-British Exhibition and the 1908 Summer Olympics came to London, the first of a number of major events in White City that attracted infrastructural investment by railway companies. Among others, the MR opened its Wood Lane station on the Hammersmith branch to serve the event. From 1927 it was used to transport the public to and from the greyhound racing at White City Stadium. The station opened and closed intermittently, and was renamed twice, to Wood Lane (White City) in 1920 and White City in 1947, before it closed in 1959 following fire damage. For the next 49 years, the Wood Lane area was served only by White City on the Central line; Hammersmith line trains passed over the lane without stopping, the nearest station on that line approximately 1 km (0.62 mi) away at Shepherd's Bush.
                
            </history>
        </information>
    </station>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <station type="opened">
        <img>
            <imgName>CharingCross.jpg</imgName>
        </img>
        <name>
            <usedName>Strand</usedName>
            <currentName>Charing Cross</currentName>
        </name>
        <information>
            <position>
                <postcode> WC2N 6DX </postcode>
                <lineAdress>
                    Embankment Pl London
                </lineAdress>
            </position>
            <openedTime>
                <date> 10 </date>
                <month> March </month>
                <year> 1906 </year>
            </openedTime>
            <zones>1</zones>
            <lines>Bakerloo</lines>
            <lines>Northern</lines>
            <usage>8.13</usage>
            <history>
                The Northern line and Bakerloo line parts of the station were originally opened as two separate stations and were combined when the now defunct Jubilee line platforms were opened. The constituent stations also underwent a number of name changes during their history.
                
                The first part of the complex, the Bakerloo line platforms, was opened as Trafalgar Square by the Baker Street &amp; Waterloo Railway (BS&amp;WR) on 10 March 1906. The Northern line platforms were opened a year later, as Charing Cross, by the Charing Cross, Euston &amp; Hampstead Railway (CCE&amp;HR, now the Charing Cross branch of the Northern line) on 22 June 1907. At its opening this station was the southern terminus of the CCE&amp;HR which ran to two northern termini at Golders Green and Highgate (now Archway) tube stations.
                
                Although both lines were owned and operated by the Underground Electric Railways Company of London (UERL), there was no direct connection below ground and passengers interchanging between the lines had to do so via two sets of lifts and the surface. In an effort to improve interchange capabilities, the CCE&amp;HR was extended the short distance south under Charing Cross main line station to connect with the BS&amp;WR and the District Railway (another UERL line), opening as such on 6 April 1914.
            </history>
        </information>
    </station>
    
    
    
</stations>