<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xslt/ass2.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE whiskies SYSTEM "../dtd/Ass.dtd">
<whiskies>
<whisky types="scotch">
    <introduction>
        <title> 
            <brand>The macallan</brand>
            <region>Speyside</region>
            <town>Craigellachie</town>
            <website target="https://www.themacallan.com">www.themacallan.com</website>
            <openingtime>open all year easter-sept, Mon-Sat; Oct-Easter, Mon-Fri</openingtime>
            <image filename="Maccallan18yo.jpg" src="../images/Maccallan18yo.jpg"></image>
        </title> 
      
        
        <intro>
            <para>In the early days of single malt being commercialized,
                it was common practice to compare the drinks to another wood-aged spirit
                with a high reputation. "This is as good as Cognac," marketeers would say. 
                In The Macallan's case they'd add terms like "first growth", which is apposite. 
                The Macallan's HQ, the whitewashed baronial Easter Elchies House, 
                dose give the whole estate a somewhat refined, chateau-like air.</para>
        </intro>
    </introduction>
   
    <body>
        <p>Although The Macallan's approach to whisky-making links it directly with the older distilleries in this cluster,
            and adds weight to the theory that the earliest ones(the distillery was founded in
            <year_established>1824</year_established>)
            tend to make the heaviest whiskies, the manner in which it has sold its whisky has always seen it exist slightly 
            off-centre from the rest of the industry. One suspects that it doesn't mind that much.</p>
        
        <p>This connection with the old ways is manifested most clearly in the stillhouse
            (or at the time of writing, stillhouses; a second one was brought on-stream in 2008), 
            where tiny spirit stills hunker over their condensers like Nibelungen dwarves.</p>
        
        <p>Reflux is a bad word here. The emphasis is on producing a spirit with guts. 
            The new make, which you can taste as one of the 
            many strokes of genius on its innovative tour - is oily, malty, and deep, but importantly, sweet. 
            It's opinionated, making it clear from day one that thais is not a spirit that will be pushed around.</p>
        
        <p>That weight is vital as The Macallan has always allied itself with ex-sherry casks. Such is the symbiotic relationship 
            with sherry that owner Edrington has casks made to its exacting specifications by the Tevasa cooperage in Jerez.</p>
        
        <p><oak_used>As has been traditional, a mix of European oak(Quercus robur), with its high tannin and aromas of clove and dried fruit,
            and American(Quercus alba), all vanilla and coconut, is used, giving whisky maker Bob Dalgarno two very different main streams
            of flavour with which to work and there are many variations within those two.</oak_used></p>
        
        <p><oak_used>In sherry casks, the oiliness of the new make is both a facilitator of the flavours seeping from the oak, and a barrier to
            aggressive tannins, preventing them from grabbing the palate like a ferret with a rabbit. Old Macallan is smooth, not grippy.
            American oak(seen also in some ex-bourbon) reveals more of the cereal and soft fruity notes.</oak_used></p>
        
        <p>When I was speaking to him for the first edition, Dalgarno was putting together a vatting of sherry oak 12-year-old from 
            a range of whiskies, each with a different hue. His deep understanding of how there is a correlation between a colour and 
            a flavour spectrum has now borne fruit in the newest Macallan range: the four-strong 1824 Series.</p>
        
        <p>This was his solution to an issue facing most producers: tightness of stock. Scotch's rapid expansion in the early part of the 
            twenty-first century caught distillers on the hop. Memories of the whisky loch of the 1980s and subsequent distillery 
            closures had meant that industry production levels remained cautions for decades. The inevitable result was a shortage of 
            mature stock when the market exploded. The solution? No Age Statement(NAS) whiskies, which free the whiskymaker from the often
            restrictive nature of age statements, allowing them to explore flavour and distillery character.</p>
        
        <p>Dalgarno's response was to look at how colour could be used as an indicator of character. The irony
            (not lost on the firm's accountants, you feel) is that the new range is more expensive to produce than the 
            whiskies its members have replaced.</p>
        
        <p>It is unlikely that the stock shortage will reoccur. Huge aircraft-hanger-sized warehouses have been built and 
            a new much-expanded distillery is currently being constructed.</p>
        
        <p>Meanwhile, The Macallan straddles the world, for many the epitome of whisky as luxury, for others a manifestation of 
            old-style single malt, with a modern twist.</p>
        
        
    </body>
    <notes>
        <new_make>
            <nose type="colour" colour="clean">Clean</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="green fruits">green fruits</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="sulphur"> Light sulphur</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="fat">fat</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="oily">oily</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="malty">malty</nose>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="fat">Fat</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="oily">oily</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="heavy">Heavy</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="green olive">Green olive</palate>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="rich">Rich</finish>
            <finish type="last" last="long">Long</finish>
        </new_make>
        
        <vintage>
            <name>Gold</name>
            <abv>40%</abv>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="baked white bread">baked white bread</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="almond butter">almond butter</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="hay"> hay</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="vanilla">vanilla</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="warm">warm</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="yeasty">yeasty freshness mixes</nose>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="substance">There's substance behind the light</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="opennose"> "open" nose</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="oil">a thickness, tougue-clinging oils</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="lemon">a vibrant lemon note</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="sweets">boiled travel sweets</palate>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="dry">Dry </finish>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="malty">malty </finish>
            <conclusion>A lighter introduction to The Macallan but full of distillery character.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="fruity and spicy">Fruity and Spicy</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>Benromach 10yo</wherenext>
        </vintage>
        
        <vintage>
            <year>15YO</year>
            <oak type="fine">Fine oak</oak>
            <abv>43%</abv>
            <nose type="colour" colour="gold">gold</nose>
            
            <nose type="flavour" flavour = "orange peel">Orange peel</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour = "melon">melon</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour = "mango">mango</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour = "vanilla pod">vanilla pod</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour = "sawdust">sawdust</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour = "hazelnut">hazelnut</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling ="polish">polish</nose>
            
            <palate type="flavour" flavour = "Nutty oak">nutty oak</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour = "cooked orchard fruits">cooked orchard fruits</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour = "black banana">black banana</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour = "Caramel toffee">caramel toffee</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour = "bracken">bracken</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour = "malt">malt</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour = "dark chocolate">dark chocolate</palate>
            
            <finish type="feeling" feeling = "complex">complex</finish>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling = "fruity">fruity</finish>
            
            <conclusion>The distillery character and "Fine Oak" casks in balance.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="fruity and spicy">Fruity and Spicy</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>Glenmorangie 18yo, Glencadam 15yo.</wherenext>
        </vintage>
        
        <vintage>
            <year>18YO</year>
            <oak type="sherry">Sherry oak</oak>
            <abv>43%</abv>
            <nose type="colour" colour="amber">Dark amber</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="fruit cake">Fruit cake</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="plum pudding">plum pudding</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="moist cake">rich moist cake</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="walnut">walnut</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="gingerbread">gingerbread</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="molasses">molasses</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="dried berries">dried berries</nose>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="rich">rich</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="mouthfilling">mouthfilling</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="Chewy">chewy</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="ripe">Very ripe</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="oily">oily</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="raisin"> rainsin</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="fig"> fig</palate>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="complex">A singed note adding to the complexity.</finish>
            <conclusion>Balance struck between the bold distillery character and rich oak.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>Dalmore 1981, Glenfarclas 15yo</wherenext>
        </vintage>
        
        <vintage>
            <name>Sienna </name>
            <abv>43%</abv>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="black cherry">Stewed black cherries</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="red plum">red plums</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="blueberry">blueberries</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" feeling="pure">purity</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" feeling="fresh">freshness</nose>
            
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="earthy">Earthy</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="thick">thick</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="tannin">supple tannins</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="candle wax"> candle wax</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="resin"> resin</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="allspice">allspice</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="clove"> clove.</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="peels"> peels</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="perfumed fruits"> perfumed fruits</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="artist's palatte"> whiff of an artist's palatte</palate>
            <finish type="flavour" flavour="raisined">Rainsined</finish>
            <finish type="last" last="long">long</finish>
            <conclusion>A country house in autumn.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>Yamazaki 18yo</wherenext>
        </vintage>
        
        <vintage>
            <year>25YO</year>
            <oak type="sherry">Sherry oak</oak>
            <abv>43%</abv>
            <nose type="colour" colour="amber">Rich amber</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="dark sweet fruits">dark sweet fruits</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="toasted almond">toasted almond</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="dried herbs">dried herbs </nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="sweet">fruit compote sweetness, the sweetness of the spirit now in its fullest expression along 
                with resin from the oak</nose>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="sweet">Very sweet. </palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="red wine">red wine notes</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="grip">Fine grip</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="mulberry">mulberry</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="cassis">cassis</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="smoke"> smoke</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="earthy">earthy</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="raisin">a full hit of raisin.</palate>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="rich">Rich</finish>
            <finish type="last" last="long">Long</finish>
            <conclusion>The sherry oak seems to link to the oil and play variations on that theme.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>The GlenDronach 1989, Benromach 1981</wherenext>
        </vintage>
        
        <vintage>
            <name>Ruby</name>
            <abv>43%</abv>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="prune">Prunes</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="dried cherries">dried cherries</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="barolo">a sweet/savoury edge akin to Barolo</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="Turkish delight">Chocolate-covered Turkish delight.</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="robust">Robust</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="sweet">Sweet</nose>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="rich">Rich</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="oloroso">Oloroso notes </palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="tannin">Assam-like tannins. </palate>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="deep">Deep</finish>
            <finish type="last" last="long">long</finish>
            <conclusion>Classical in structure and aromatics, with added vinous sweetness.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>Aberlour A'Bunadh</wherenext>
        </vintage>
    </notes>
</whisky>


<whisky types="scotch">
    <introduction>
        <title>
            <brand>Glenfiddich</brand>
            <region>Speyside</region>
            <town>Dufftown</town>
            <website target="https://www.glenfiddich.com">www.glenfiddich.com</website>
            <openingtime>Open all year MON-SUN</openingtime>
            <image filename="Glenfiddich12yo.jpg" src="../images/Glenfiddich12yo.jpg"></image>
        </title>
        <intro>
            <para>As the world's best-selling single malt and the first distillery to open its doors (in 1969), it would be easy for a first-time
                visitor to Glenfiddich to expect a somewhat cliched recreation of whisky-making, but instead they get the opposite.
                This is a huge (14-hectare/35-acre) working site with its own cooperage, coppersmith, bottling line 
                (all Glenfiddich is bottled on site), warehousing...and three distilleries.
                Glenfiddich is both a modern single malt brand, but also a distillery where - despite the scale - 
                traditional wthos of self-sufficiency has been retained.</para>
        </intro>
    </introduction>
    <body>
        <p>Built by William Grant in <year_established>1886</year_established> and still owned by his descendants, the first spirit ran from its small stills(bought from Cardhu)
            on Christmas Day the following year. You can't help but feel that even in those early days, the founder had an eye on marketing.
        </p>
        <p>Glenfiddich is about lightness of character, but walking into the stillhouse you'd think it would produce a similar style to Macallan.
            The stills are tiny and, science tells us, small stills will tend to produce a heavy, often sulphury new make.
            Nose Glenfiddich however and it's all grass, green apple, and pear. 
            "We cut at high strength which is how we get this estery, clean spirit," says William Grant's master blender Brian Kinsman.
            "If we ran any deeper and cut later it would be much heavier and potentially sulphury."
        </p>
        <p>So is this a case of a distillery running against type? "Not as far as we can tell," says Kinsman.
            "Glenfiddich, from our records, has always been light. The stills have always been that shape, 
            and as demand grew we just built more of them." If they'd stuck at four stills and tried to cope with increased sales they'd 
            have had to widen the cut in order to get more liquid - and changed the style.
            Buliding new stills was the only option in order to retain character.
            The fact that there are 28 stills in two stillhouses shows how big that demand is.
        </p>
        <p>This lack of sulphur is also advantageous, Kinsman says, "as you don't have to overcome something before you start getting 
            additive maturation". Even at three years of age, Glenfiddich is picking up wood notes, oak shavings in refill; 
            rope pineapple and creamy vanilla in first-fill bourbon; marmalade and sultana in first-fill European...all cut with that green freshness.
        </p>
        <p>A significant improvement in wood management and a rejigging of the wood mix has resulted in a much more coherent range.
            Whereas in the past Glenfiddich had a somewhat frustrating randomness about it, now there's a thread given by European oak,
            which is increased slowly with each age expression(bar the 21yo rum finish).
            As age takes hold, so the green apples of youth ripen, the cut grass dries, and a chocolate note slowly develops.
            For a light whisky, it manages to hold its own...even at 40 and 50 years.
            "The new make is light on the nose but it matures incredibly well," says Kinsman.
            "I think that freshness and intensity belies how much complexity is in there." For me, it seems to ride on a wave of oak,
            buoyed up by it but always remaining identifiably Glenfiddich.
        </p>
        <p>The integration of oak and spirit is best personified by the pioneering establishment in 1998 of a solera vat for the 15yo.
            This Jerezano technique of gractional blending involves only removing 50 per cent of the vat's contents for each bottling.
            This is then replaced with a mix comprising of 70 per cent from refill bourbon, 20 per cent from European oak, 
            and 10 per cent in virgin oak. Solera blending not only adds depth (some whiskies have been there since 1998) 
            but a different, softer mouthfeel. A similar technique is employed with the 40yo whose never-emptied vat contains remnants 
            from the 1920s. Three new solera vats have recently been installed for its new "Cask" range.
        </p>
        <p>It is this general amenability that holds the key to Glenfiddich's long-term ageing ability - and one might guess,
            is also the secret of its commercial success as well.
        </p>
        
    </body>
    <notes>
        <new_make>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="crisp">crisp</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="clean">clean</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="grassy">grassy</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="green apple">green apple</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="pineapple">ripe pineapple</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" feeling="pure">pure</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" feeling="fresh">fresh</nose>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="pear">pears</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="grass">grass</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="easter">easter</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="cereal">Light cereal background</palate>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="light">light</finish>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="fresh">fresh</finish>
        </new_make>
        
        <vintage>
            <year>12YO</year>
            <abv>40%</abv>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="vanilla">vanilla</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="red apple">red apple</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="sultana">sultana</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="milk chocolate">milk chocolate</nose>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="sweet">pears</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="gentle">gentle</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="smooth">smooth</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="vanilla">vanilla</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="christmas pudding">christmas pudding</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="mixed fruits">mixed fruits</palate>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="buttery">buttery</finish>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="grassy">grassy</finish>
            <conclusion>The green notes of new make have now deepened and ripened. Some European oak has added depth.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="fragrant and floral">Fragrant and Floral</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>The Glenlivet 12yo, anCnoc 16yo</wherenext>
        </vintage>
        
        <vintage>
            <year>15YO</year>
            <abv>40%</abv>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="ripe">ripe</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="soft">soft</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="plum jam">plum jam</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="baked apple">baked apple</nose>
            
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="soft">soft</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="silky">silky</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="black fruit">stewed black fruit</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="coconut">coconut</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="dried grass">dried grass</palate>
            
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="ripe">ripe</finish>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="full">full</finish>
            <conclusion>Solera adds a richer depth and feel.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>Glencadam 1978, Blair Atholl 12yo</wherenext>
        </vintage>
        
        <vintage>
            <year>18YO</year>
            <abv>40%</abv>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="raisin">raisin</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="dried fruits">dried fruits</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="mulberry">mulberry</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="dark chocolate">dark chocolate</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="hay">hay</nose>
            
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="grip">grip</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="dark fruits">Concertrated dark fruits</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="Cacao">Cacao</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="cedar">cedar</palate>
            
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="smooth">smooth</finish>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="long">long</finish>
            <finish type="feeling" feeling="sweet">sweet</finish>
            <conclusion>The midpoint of the range as the freshness of youth gives way to the dark mysteries of age.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>Jura 16yo, Royal Lochnagar Selected Reserve</wherenext>
        </vintage>
        
        
        <vintage>
            <year>21YO</year>
            <abv>40%</abv>
            <nose type="colour" colour="amber">Deep amber</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="sweet">sweet</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="oaky">oaky</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="coffee">coffee</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="cacao">cacao</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="cedar">a touch of cedar</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="barley sugar">Barley sugar</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="caramel toffee">caramel toffee</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="black banana">black banana</nose>
            
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="rich">rich</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="sweet">sweet</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="tannin">light tannins</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="Mocha">Mocha</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="bitter chocolate">bitter chocolate</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="forest floor">forest floor</palate>
            
            <finish type="flavour" flavour="dry oak">dry oak</finish>
            <finish type="flavour" flavour="leafy">leafy</finish>
            <conclusion>Has maturity, this has been given a finishing period in rum cask.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="fruity and spicy">Fruity and Spicy</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>Balblair 1990, Longmorn 16yo</wherenext>
        </vintage>
        
        
        <vintage>
            <year>30YO</year>
            <abv>40%</abv>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="Resinous">Resinous</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="thick">thick</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="ripe">ripe</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="rich">rich</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="rancioed">rancioed</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="energetic lift">surprising energetic lift</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="cigar humidor">Cigar humidor</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="nutty">nuttiness</nose>
            
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="smooth">smooth</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="silky">silky</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="mossiness">Flows over the tougue with a slight mossiness.</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="Chocolate">Chocolate</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="coffee">coffee</palate>
            
            <finish type="flavour" flavour="fade">Fading</finish>
            <finish type="flavour" flavour="sweet">has residual sweetness</finish>
            <conclusion>The fruits have now been fully concentrated but they dry grassiness is retained giving a vestigial freshness.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>Macallan 25yo Sherry Oak, Glen Grant 25yo</wherenext>
        </vintage>
        
        
        <vintage>
            <year>40YO</year>
            <abv>43.5%</abv>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="Resinous">Resinous</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="oily">oily</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="deep">deep</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="rich">rich</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" feeling="rancio">rancio</nose>
            
            <nose type="feeling" flavour="Herbs">Herbs</nose>
            <nose type="feeling" flavour="damp moss">damp moss</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="grass">grassiness</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="beeswax">Beeswax</nose>
            <nose type="flavour" flavour="herbal">herbal</nose>
            
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="big">big</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="rounded">rounded</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="elegant">elegant</palate>
            <palate type="feeling" feeling="rich">rich</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="Chocolate">Chocolate</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="plum">plum</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="espresso">espresso</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="mulberry">mulberry</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="nutty">nutty</palate>
            <palate type="flavour" flavour="sherry">sherry</palate>
            
            <finish type="flavour" flavour="herbal">herbal</finish>
            <finish type="flavour" last="long">long</finish>
            <conclusion>A solera-style system used here with some of the original batch, containing whiskies from the 1920s to the 1940s, kept in the vat.</conclusion>
            <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
            <wherenext>Dalmore, Candela 50yo</wherenext>
        </vintage>
    </notes>
</whisky>
    
    <whisky types="scotch">
        <introduction>
            <title>
                <brand>The GlenDronach</brand>
                <region>Highland</region>
                <town>Forgue, By Huntly</town>
                <website target="https://www.glendronachdistillery.com">www.glendronachdistillery.com</website>
                <openingtime>Open all year OCT-APR, MON-FRI; MAY-SPET, MON-SUN</openingtime>
                <image filename="GlenDronach-15yo.jpg" src="../images/GlenDronach-15yo.jpg"></image>
            </title>
            <intro>
                <para>The last of the Garioch trio lies in the village of Forgue and was built in <year_established>1826</year_established> by a consortium of local farmers.
                    Unusually, in an industry where consolidation has always been the norm, The GlenDronach remained in private hands until 1960
                    when it became part of Teacher's, the blending house that also owned nearby distillery Ardmore.
                </para>
            </intro>
        </introduction>
        <body>
            <p>Teacher's is quite a muscular blend and The GlenDronach was a good fit. This is a big spirit whose new make is weighty with
                a buttery effect that spreads over the tougue. It's built to cope with prolonged ageing - and ex-sherry casks.
                Though one-time owner Allied tried to make it a single-malt brand like its Garioch neighbours, The GlenDronach seemed 
                destined to be a cult until it was bought in 2006 by The BenRiach's Billy Walker. The focus is now single malt.
            </p>
            <p>Its muscularity, believes manager Alan McConnochie, lies in an adherence to traditional methods, such as a rake system in the mash tun.
                "It's a funny thing," he says. "We get the same malt as The BenRiach, but if you stick your head in the mash tun here, 
                the smell is totally different. They say water doesn't make a difference? I'm not so sure."
            </p>
            <p>Long ferments in wooden washbacks take the wash to a slow distillation. "There's little reflux," says McConnochie.
                "There's no stress here: none of that running up and down the inside of the still." Neither did he notice a difference 
                when the coal fires were extinguished in 2005.
            </p>
            <p>The GlenDronach reminds me a little of former British Prime Minister Gordon Brown. It is a malt of serious mien whose brief 
                show of youthful exuberance in the 12yo version soon deepens, becoming serious as it does, seemingly being drawn back into 
                the heavy earth of its birth. The new owner is now giving the whisky five years in ex-bourbon casks before re-racking into 
                oloroso sherry and sometimes from there into Pedro Ximenez sherry casks.
            </p>
            <p>"People associate The GlenDronach with sherry," says McConnochie. "It's a lot harder to overpower it with wood, 
                which is a nice problem to have!" The muscularity of the farmlands shows through once more.
            </p>
        </body>
        <notes>
            <new_make>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="heavy">heavy</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="sweet">sweet</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="rich">rich</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="earthy">earthy</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="fruity">fruity</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="Robust">Robust</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="buttery">buttery in texture adding weight and suppleness</palate>
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="long">very long</finish>
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="fruity">fruity</finish>
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="plum">plum</finish>
            </new_make>
            
            
            <vintage>
                <year>12YO</year>
                <abv>43%</abv>
                <nose type="colour" colour="gold">Deep gold</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="sweet">sweet</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="sherried">sherried</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="plum stone">plum stone</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="cereal">dusty cereal</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="big">big</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="rich">rich</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="concentrated">concentrated</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="unctuous">Unctuous</palate>
                
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="dried fruits">dried fruits</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="damson">damson</palate>
                <finish type="feeling" flavour="Earth">Earth</finish>
                <finish type="feeling" flavour="smoke">smoke</finish>
                <conclusion>Already full and deep with a spark of adolescent cheekiness.</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>Glenfiddich 15yo, Cragganmore 12yo, Glenfarclas 12yo</wherenext>
            </vintage>
            
            <vintage>
                <year>18YO</year>
                <name>Allardice</name>
                <abv>46%</abv>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="sherried">sherried</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="layered">layered</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="velvety">velvety</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="dried red fruits">dried red fruits</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="musk">musk</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="raisins">raisins</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="toffee">Treacle toffee</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="grip">light grip</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="deep">depth</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="liquorice root">liquorice root</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="toffee">Treacle toffee</palate>
                
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="sweet">sweet</finish>
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="long">long</finish>
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="concentrated fruits">concentrated fruits</finish>
                <conclusion>This is unreconstructed, old-style single malt.</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>Karuizawa(1980s), The Macallan 18yo</wherenext>
            </vintage>
            
            
            <vintage>
                <year>21YO</year>
                <name>Parliament</name>
                <abv>48%</abv>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="Big">Big</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="Wood oil">Wood oil</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="yew trees">yew trees</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="dusty">dusty</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="dried fruits">dried fruits</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="raisins">raisins</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="figs">figs</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="dates">dates</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="coffee grounds">coffee grounds</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="mocha">mocha</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="molasses">molasses</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="ripe">ripe</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="full">full</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="firm">firm</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="smoke">smoke</palate>
                
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="Baked fruits">Baked fruits</finish>
                <finish type="last" last="long">length</finish>
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="weight">heft</finish>
                
                <conclusion>Powerful and complex.</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>Karuizawa (1970s), Glenfarclas 30yo</wherenext>
            </vintage>
        </notes>
    </whisky>
    
    
    <whisky types="scotch">
        <introduction>
            <title>
                <brand>Dalmore and Invergordon</brand>
                <region>Highland</region>
                <town>Alness</town>
                <website target="https://www.thedalmore.com">www.thedalmore.com</website>
                <openingtime>Open all year APR-OCT MON-SAT, NOV-MAR MON-FRI</openingtime>
                <image filename="1981-Dalmore.png" src="../images/1981-Dalmore.png"></image>
            </title>
            <intro>
                <para>A heightened sense of individuality is the key to all the whiskies from this northest coast and Dalmore couldn't be any 
                    further from Teaninich's steeliness. This is a whisky that revels in its richness and depth. If Teaninich seems to speak 
                    of an eternal cold spring, at Dalmore, hard on the shores of the Cromarty Firth, it's as if it is autumn all year round. 
                    You leave with berry juice filling your mouth.
                </para>
            </intro>
        </introduction>
        <body>
            <p>Established in <year_established>1839</year_established>, Dalmore's distillation regime seems to have been born out of some manic episode on the part of the founder.
                The wash stills have flat tops and lyne arms sticking out of thesides, the spirit stills have water jacket mufflers round their necks.
                To make matters more complicated, they're all different sizes.
            </p>
            <p>Dalmore has two stillhouses. The two wash stills in the old stillhouse differ in size to each other; the two in the new stillhouse 
                match in size, but differ to those in the old stillhouse. Result? Different strengths and character of low wines.
                The design similarity but size discrepancy is repeated in the spirit stills. At Dalmore, the strength of thod charge will vary because 
                the stills are all different shapes and sizes. At any point there might be high-strength feints arriving from the spirit-still 
                side along with high-strength low wines from the wash-still side; equally there might be low-strength feints and low-strength 
                low wines; or high-strength feints and low-strength low wines, etc. That's a myraid different flavours in the new make.
            </p>
            <p>This weight also helps dictate Dalmore's wood policy. This is a spirit that revels in the close attentions of ex-sherry casks, which add
                structure but also pick up the sweetness and take it deep into mysterious areas. At 5 years it seems to be absorbing wood but keeping its
                counsel; even at 12 there's a feeling the forces of darkness are massing behind the oaken gates. Only at 15 years does the sleek Dalmore 
                begin to step out. 
            </p>
            <p>In recent years this forgotten giant has been relaunched, propelling itself into the luxury arena with a number of ultra-aged, 
                ultra-expensive expressions. Sirius, Candela, and Selene all have in excess of 50 years in cask and are filled with exotic concentrated
                rancio scents of maturity.
            </p>
            <p>Three miles up the coast, a different scent pervades the air: one of cooking cereal. This is the site of Scotland's most northerly grain
                distillery, Invergordon. It may seem unusual to find a type of whisky considered to be urban in such a rural setting, but Invergordon
                has a long industry history. An aluminium smelter ran until 1981, while a deep-water harbour resulted in the building of a naval yard. Today,
                wind turbines and oil rigs are manufactured and repaired here and on the other shore of the firth at Nigg Bay.
            </p>
            <p>When the naval yard closed in the late 1950s, a new source of employment was needed and building a distillery seemed a perfectly
                sensible idea. There were crops from the fertile surrounding farmlands, a port, and a workforce. It was the perfect fusion of
                agriculture and manufacturing heritage.
            </p>
            <p>Invergordon started producing from a Coffey still in 1960s, the number soon rising to four sets. Today, it alternates between wheat
                and maize to produce in the region of 36 million litres(eight million gallons) a year, a make that is spicy and slightly lactic. It's 
                most widely used in owner Whyte and Mackay's blends, but will be used by other non-group blenders. There was, briefly, a single grain
                bottling, The Invergordon, targeted at women in the early 1990s, and a malt distillery, Ben Wyvis, ran for 12 years from 1965-77.
                Its still are now at Glengyle.
            </p>
        </body>
        <notes>
            <new_make>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="kumquat">kumquat</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="black fruits">sweet black fruits</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="orange juice">orange juice</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="Ripe">Ripe</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="heavy">heavy</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="cereal">cereal</palate>
                
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="Fresh">Fresh</finish>
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="citrus">citrus</finish>
            </new_make>
            
            <vintage>
                <year>12YO</year>
                <abv>40%</abv>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="restrained">restrained</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="crisp">crisp</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="malt">malt</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="dried fruits">dried fruits</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="Clean">Clean</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="vanilla">vanilla</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="christmas cakes">christmas cakes</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="orange peel">orange peel</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="currant leaf">currant leaf</palate>
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="long">long</finish>
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="fruity">fruity</finish>
                <conclusion>Already sweetening but still finding its way.</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="fruity and spicy">Fruity and Spicy</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>Edradour 1996 Oloroso Finish</wherenext>
            </vintage>
            
            <vintage>
                <year>15YO</year>
                <abv>40%</abv>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="sweet">sweet</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="Substaintial">Substaintial</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="weighty">weighty</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="sherried">heavy sherry influence</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="jammy">Jammy</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="hedgerow fruits">hedgerow fruits</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="leaf">leaf</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="soft">soft</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="gentle">gentle</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="Dried fruits">Dried fruits</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="tea">orange pekoe tea</palate>
                
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="Kumquat">Kumquat</finish>
                <conclusion>A mix of bold sherry casks; the distillery and wood have achieved an equilibrium at this age.</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>The Singleton of Dufftown 12yo</wherenext>
            </vintage>
            
            <vintage>
                <year>1981</year>
                <name>Matusalem</name>
                <abv>44%</abv>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="Round">Round</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="rich">rich</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="mulberry">mulberry</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="coffee">coffee</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="rancio">cheese-like rancio</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="walnut">walnut</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="orange">Seville orange</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="Long">Long</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="soft">soft</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="powerful">powerful</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="cigar">Robusto cigar</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="leaf mulch">leaf mulch</palate>
                
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="long">long</finish>
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="grip">light grip</finish>
                <conclusion>Intense, powerful thanks to sweet sherry cask.</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="rich and round">Rich and Round</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>Aberlour 25yo, The Macallan 18yo Sherry</wherenext>
            </vintage>
            
            <vintage>
                <year>15YO</year>
                <name>Invergordon, cask sample</name>
                <abv>62%</abv>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="sweet">sweet</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="sour">sour</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="vegetal">vegetal</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="flower stalls">flower stalls</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="cheese rind">light cheese rind</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="grass">grass clippings</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="sweet">sweet</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="phenolic">light phenolic</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="firm">firm</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="rum">Trinidadian rum</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="cereal">cereal</palate>
                
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="Bitter chocolate">Bitter chocolate</finish>
                <conclusion>The most individual of Scotland's grains.</conclusion>
            </vintage>
        </notes>
    </whisky>
    
    
    <whisky types="scotch">
        <introduction>
            <title>
                <brand>Auchentoshan</brand>
                <region>Lowland</region>
                <town>Auchentoshan</town>
                <website target="https://www.auchentoshan.com">www.auchentoshan.com</website>
                <openingtime>open all year, MON-SUN</openingtime>
                <image filename="Auchentoshan-12YO.jpg" src="../images/Auchentoshan-12YO.jpg"></image>
            </title>
            <intro>
                <para>Though the fourthof the handful of Lowlanders may be less than romantically situated - between the River Clyde and 
                    the main road from Glasgow to Loch Lomond - it offers up another way of producing light: triple-distillation.
                    In the nineteenth century, this was a fairly common method of production, eapecially in the Lowland belt, perhaps as 
                    a result of Irish immigration, or even as an attempt to copy what at that time was a more successful whisky style. 
                    Economics at work again. Today, however, Auchentoshan (aka. "Auchie") is the only Scottish distillery that does it exclusively.
                </para>
            </intro>
        </introduction>
        <body>
            <p>Here, triple-distillation is used to build strength and lighten character, ending up with with a fresh, highly focused new make.
                The charge for the third(spirit) stills is made uo of hig-strength "heads" from the intermediate.
                When this is distilled the spirit cut is taken between 82-80%abv. "It's on spirit for maybe 15 minutes," 
                says Iain McCallum, blender at owner Morrison Bowmore.
                "Obviously that's giving us a light character, but I don't want neutrality. Auchentoshan should have sweetness, a malty note, 
                citric fruits and, as it matures, a hazelnut character." Auchie's inherent delicacy of character means that McCallum cannot 
                be too heavy-handed with oak.
            </p>
            <p>"It's such a light spirit that it could easily be swamped. I believe strongly in having the character of the spirit 
                coming through the heart of the brand," says McCallum. "And with Auchie you have to take it easy with the oak."
            </p>
            <p>A clever balancing act is therefore required to give the young spirit a sufficient boost from wood: enough to underpin its 
                delicacy with layers of flavour. Equally, in older expressions the key is having a gentle oaken touch.
            </p>
            <p>The lightness of the spirit also means Auchie has a greater degree of flexibility than bolder, stronger, beasts.
                As a result, the firm has been working extensively with bartenders to develop Auchie as a base for long and mixed drinks.
            </p>
            <p>They do things differently beside the Clyde, but it isn't blindly percerse, it is done for a reason: it works.
            </p>
        </body>
        <notes>
            <new_make>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="light">kumquat</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="intense">sweet black fruits</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="Pink rhubarb">Pink rhubarb</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="sweet cardboard">sweet cardboard</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="banana peel">banana peel</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="leafy">leafy</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="tight">tight</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="hot">hot</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="biscuity">biscuity</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="lemon">intense lemon lift</palate>
                
                <finish type="last" last="quick">quick</finish>
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="apple">apple</finish>
            </new_make>
            
            <vintage>
                <year>NAS</year>
                <name>Classic</name>
                <abv>40%</abv>
                <nose type="colour" colour="gold">Light gold</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="oak">Sweet oak</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="dusty">Slightly dusty</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="floral">light floral note</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="coconut">touches of coconut matting from oak</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="Sweet">Sweet</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="nutty">nutty</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="vanilla">vanilla</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="chocolate">chocolate</palate>
                
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="fresh">fresh</finish>
                <conclusion>Deftly handled oak allows character to show.</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="malty and dry">Malty and Dry</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>Tamnavulin 12yo, Glen Spey 12yo</wherenext>
            </vintage>
            
            
            <vintage>
                <year>12YO</year>
                <abv>40%</abv>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="oak">oak leads the way</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="bun">hot cross bun</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="almond">almond</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="citrus">Citrus lift</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="Clean">Clean</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="soft">soft</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="cereal">cereal</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="leafy">leafy</palate>
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="crisp">crisp</finish>
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="clean">clean</finish>
                <conclusion>Identifiably Auchie.</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="malty and dry">Malty and Dry</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>Macduff 1984</wherenext>
            </vintage>
            
            
            <vintage>
                <year>21YO</year>
                <abv>43%</abv>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="mature">Slightly funky maturity</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="fresh">freshness</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="dark fruits">Concentrated dark fruits</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="dry spices">coriander</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="chestnut">roast chestnut</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="dusty">intense dustiness</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="rich">rich</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="liquorous">liquorous</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="lavebder">lavebder</palate>
                
                <finish type="flavour" feeling="perfumed">Perfumed</finish>
                <conclusion>Even at 21 years a light spirit holds its own. </conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="fruity and spicy">Fruity and Spicy</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>The Glenlivet 18yo, Benromach 25yo</wherenext>
            </vintage>
        </notes>
    </whisky>
    
    
    <whisky types="scotch">
        <introduction>
            <title>
                <brand>Laphroaig</brand>
                <region>Islay</region>
                <town>Port Ellen</town>
                <website target="https://www.laphroaig.com">www.laphroaig.com</website>
                <openingtime>Open all year MAR-DEC, MON-SUN; JAN-FEB, MON-FRI</openingtime>
                <image filename="laphroaig-10yo.jpg" src="../images/laphroaig-10yo.jpg"></image>
            </title>
            <intro>
                <para>The final member of the Kildalton trio lies little more than a couple of miles from Lagavulin. It too is smoky, yet once
                    again the character of that smoke is fundamentally different to its neighbours'. Laphroaig is heavy and rooty,
                    like walking down a freshly tarred seaside road on a hot day. It was a style that was envied by its neighbour at one time, 
                    Sir Peter Mackie, who owned Lagavulin - he had lost the agency for Laphroaig in 1907. He built a replica, called Malt Mill, 
                    at Lagavulin using the same water, same stills, and even(after financial inducement) the same distiller. The whisky was different. 
                    "It's something that scientists try to explain, but can't," says Laphroaig's manager, John Campbell.
                    "Character is about location, maybe that's why distilleries are all across Scotland, rather than in one super-distillery. 
                    It could be down to altitude, it could be proximity to the sea, it could be humidity...I don't know, but it exists."
                </para>
            </intro>
        </introduction>
        <body>
            <p>It does also lie within the creative process at the distillery. Laphroaig still operates its own floor maltings, 
                which provide up to 20 per cent of its requirements. For Campbell, the maltings aren't there as a sop for tourists, 
                they certainly don't offer any savings in fixed cost, but they do provide a different character. "We get a different 
                smokiness here than we get from Port Ellen[malt]. We kiln differently, we peat and then dry at low temperatures. 
                This gives us higher levels of cresol [a key phenol] and it's this that gives you that tarry note in the spirit. 
                It wouldn't be there without the floor maltings."
            </p>
            <p>The stillhouse is, inevitably, different. There are seven stills for starters, while on the spirit side there are two 
                different sizes, with one twice the size of the other three. "We are effectively making two different spirits, 
                which we then marry together before casking," says Campbell.
            </p>
            <p>Ardbeg and Lagavulin both strive for an element of reflux to get aweeter estery notes. Laphroaig on the other hand, 
                steers the other way. Here, Campbell wants to hold onto that heavy tarry weight that means having the longest foreshot 
                run in the industry (45 minutes) so that those sweet esters at the start of the run are recycled rather than collected. 
                "We cut at 60%abv, which isn't as low as some, but because we get less of the estery notes there is a larger percentage 
                of smokiness, so the spirit seems heavier."
            </p>
            <p>The sweetness that does exist within Laphroaig is found from its virtually exclusive use of American oak barrels - 
                all of which come from Maker's Mark. "For consistency", says Campbell. It's this vanilla character that smoothes away 
                the more rugged edge of the new make and adds a subtle sweet drive to the mature spirit. A good example of this process 
                is the Quarter Cask release in which young Laphroaig is given a short period of extra maturation in the new tiny, 
                "quarter" casks made from American oak. The vanilla and the smoke are here at their peak.
            </p>
            <p>For Campbell though Laphroaig is more than just technology, it's people. "I'd say that we were the result of the people 
                who have worked here. People have influenced the style and the sttitude to making whisky, none more so than Ian Hunter 
                [who owned it from 1924-54]. It was he who created the recipe that we have now. In the 1920s we were mucking around and 
                it really wasn't until 1940, after Prohibition, that he began to source ex-bourbon casks and mature the whisky on site."
            </p>
            <p>So, it comes back to location again. "A traditional warehouse gives more body to the whisky, maybe because you get more 
                oxidation in a damp dunnage than the rack. We have both on site and I know that there is a difference." 
                Maybe he should have told Sir Peter Mackie.
            </p>
        </body>
        <notes>
            <new_make>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="Heavy">Heavy</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="oily">Oilier than its neighbours</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="complex">Has complexity</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="smoke">tarry smoke</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="medicinal">iodine</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="medicinal">hospital</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="malt">crisp maltiness</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="gentian root">gentian root</nose>
                
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="ember">Hot embers followed by the rich spread of smoke. Both dark and clean.</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="road">Hot roads on a summer day by the sea.</palate>
                
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="dry">dry</finish>
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="clean">clean</finish>
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="crisp">crisp</finish>
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="smoky">smoky</finish>
            </new_make>
            
            <vintage>
                <year>10YO</year>
                <abv>40%</abv>
                <nose type="colour" colour="gold">rich gold</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="oak">sweet oak</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="Wood oil">Wood oil</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="pine woods">pine woods</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="Seashore">Seashore</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="wintergreen">wintergreen</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="nutty">Nutty</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="medicinal">iodine</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="smooth">smooth</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="soft">soft</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="tarry">tarry</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="vanilla">plenty of vanilla accents</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="smoke">smoke</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="oak">oak</palate>
                <finish type="last" last="long">long</finish>
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="smoke">lightly peppery smoke</finish>
                <conclusion>The key here is the balance between the dry(smoke) and sweet(oak).</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="smoky and peaty">Smoky and Peaty</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>Ardbeg 10yo</wherenext>
            </vintage>
            
            <vintage>
                <year>18YO</year>
                <abv>48%</abv>
                <nose type="colour" colour="gold">rich gold</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="Restrained">Restrained</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="spicy">a spicier edge alongside that creamy oak</nose>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="gentle">gentle</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="smoke">The smoke, having been given more time with the oak</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="medicinal">iodine</nose>
                
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="nutty">Walnut</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="raisin">raisin</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="citric">citric</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="smoke">smoke</palate>
                
                <finish type="flavour" flavour="cashew">Smoked salted cashew</finish>
                <conclusion>A toned-down example.</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="smoky and peaty">Smoky and Peaty</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>Caol lla 18yo</wherenext>
            </vintage>
            
            <vintage>
                <year>25YO</year>
                <abv>51%</abv>
                <nose type="feeling" feeling="smoky">smoky</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="Soy sauce">Soy sauce</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="fishboxes">fishboxes</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="dried tar">dried tar</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="tobacco">heavy tobacco</nose>
                <nose type="flavour" flavour="lobster creels">burning lobster creels</nose>
                
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="gentle">gentle</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="thick">Age has thickened it</palate>
                <palate type="feeling" feeling="complex">coherent with full integration(and therefore complexity) of distillery character</palate>
                <palate type="flavour" flavour="oak">oak plus new exotic flavours.</palate>
                
                <finish type="feeling" feeling="tarry">Still tarry</finish>
                
                <conclusion>Smoke doesn't disappear, it simply becomes more concentrated and absorbed into the overall flavour.</conclusion>
                <flavourcamp type="smoky and peaty">Smoky and Peaty</flavourcamp>
                <wherenext>Ardbeg Lord of the Isles 25yo</wherenext>
            </vintage>
        </notes>
    </whisky>
    
</whiskies>